A Guide to the JMU Nursing Department Records, 1951-2015 (bulk 1972- 2001): UA 0006
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
- Subject Files, 1951-2015
  - State Board of Nursing Survey Visit, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - State Board of Nursing Survey Visit, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Statement of Readiness, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Statistics, 1982-1989 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Student Directories, 1986, 1987, 1997-2000, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Student Nurses Association of Virginia Convention, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Support Data, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Support Data for President Carrier, 1974-1977 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - ULN Project Area I- Task Force to Explore Internships, 1978-1980 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Uniforms, Student, 1980-1983 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - VA State Board of Nursing, 1974-1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - VA State Board of Nursing Progress Reports, 1975-1977 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - VA State Board of Nursing Prospectus Approval, 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - VA State Board of Nursing: Reports, Data, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - VA State Board of Nursing: Report of Site Visit, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - VA State Board of Nursing: Supplemental to Letter of Intent, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - VA State Health Department: Agreement between Madison College and VA State Health Department, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - VA State Health Department (Correspondence, Data, Misc.), 1966, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Virginia State Board of Nursing, 1973-1975 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Virginia State Board of Nursing Proposal, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Photographs, 1980-2015 (bulk 1982-1999)
  Arranged chronologically, with one exception (box 18, folder 11) in compliance with original order received, and then alphabetically.
  Series 4: Photographs, 1980-2015 (bulk 1982-1999) consists almost entirely of photographs and negatives documenting professional, curricular, and social happenings in the Department of Nursing. In general, folders titled "Photos, xxxx" contain photos concerning the graduating class of the most recent date in the title. Some of the photos are labeled but the majority are not. Events of interest, which can be found throughout many folders with duplicates throughout, include: Class Pinning Ceremonies, some with Dr. Carrier and Dr. Dake, student and faculty meetings and conferences, students involved in practicum instruction, and Career Days. Individual class photos of every graduating nursing student can be found in years 1993-1996, 1998-2000. Some photos include Dr. Carrier, Dr. Linwood Rose, fifth president of JMU, and Virginia Senator Mark Warner. Other photos show campus construction of Phillips Hall and an unidentified building on East Campus. Box 17, folder 3 and box 18, folder 3 contain photos of Wilson Hall as seen from Bridgeforth Stadium. In addition, there are many photos throughout the series that have sticky notes with stars on the back. There is one photo album in this series that documents the first two years of the program from the faculty/staff perspective. There are many loose photos and labels throughout the album.
  - Photos, 1980-1986, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Color Photos (Folder 1 of 2), 1980, 1992, 2014, 2015, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Color Photos (Folder 2 of 2), 1980, 1992, 2014, 2015, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Photo Album, 1982, 1984, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Photos, 1983, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Photos, 1984, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Photos, 1985, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Photos, 1986, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Photos, 1987, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Photos, 1987, 1988, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Class Photos, 1987, 1993-1996, 2001, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Negatives, 1987, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Photos, 1998, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Photos, 1989, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Photos, 1990, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Photos, 1991, 1992, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Photos, 1992, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Photos, 1991, 1993, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Photos, 1994, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Poster Presentation Photos, 1994, 1996, 1999, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Photos, 1995, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Photos, 1996, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Photos, 1997, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Class Photos, 1997, 1999, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Photos, 1998, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Photos, 1999, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Photos, 2000, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Photos, 2001, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Photos, 2002, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Photos, 2005, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Class Photo Banners, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Class Pix CD, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Black and White Photos, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Photos, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
- Scrapbooks, 1982-2007 (bulk 2000-2007)
  Series 5: Scrapbooks, 1982-2007 (bulk 2000-2007) contains eight scrapbooks relating to the Nursing Department. The Class of 1982 scrapbook documents the first two years of the Department of Nursing from the student perspective, including photos of practicum, the 1982 Student Nurse Association of Virginia (SNAV) convention, meetings with Eastern Mennonite College (now Eastern Mennonite University) students, pinning, and commencement. The majority of scrapbooks highlight academic years from 2000-2007 through the Nursing Student Association (NSA), JMU's chapter of the National Student Nurses' Association, that promotes the professional and personal development of student nurses'. The NSA scrapbooks document service and social activities that the chapter participated in during the year. The Virginia Nursing Student Association holds scrapbook competitions for Virginia NSA chapters. Some activities documented in the scrapbooks include: Relay for Life, Senior Prom, recruitment, fundraising, and holidays.
  - Class of 1982 Scrapbook, 1982, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Nursing Student Association Scrapbook, 2000-2001 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Nursing Student Association Scrapbook, 2001-2002 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Nursing Student Association Scrapbook, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Nursing Student Association Scrapbook- Community Service Projects, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Nursing Student Association Scrapbook, 2004-2005 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Nursing Student Association Scrapbook, 2005-2006 (Box OV 1)
  - Nursing Student Association Scrapbook, 2006-2007 (Box OV 1)